So, thank you. Firstly, thank you so
much because I reached out to you when
we were exploring. Everyone here was so
excited about the opportunity to show
this print, but we really weren't sure
we would be able to. So, so indebted to
you and everyone in in the room is
indebted to you tonight as well. Um, I
did want to start with the, you know,
the elephant in the room around the
print. It has become so scarce. Um, how
does uh how does this version to start
with this version before we talk about
the film itself, but how does this
version sort of exist as sort of
folklore within Lucasfilm now? Oh, it's
incredible folklore. I have to say that
even when I came into the company, there
was endless conversation about where
everything was and what was in fact the
first print. And it's quite remarkable.
What you're going to see is in fact the
first print. And I'm not even sure
there's another one quite like it. Yeah.
You know, it's that rare. There's so
much tinkering that's gone on over the
years and things that George decided,
I'm going to change this. I'm going to
try that. I'm going to And then
everybody kind of lost track of what it
was. Although I understand. Edgar, are
you in here?
Yeah, he's there. cuz your brother is in
here and I understand you may know more
far more than I do. I don't want to
intro the phone.
So, okay. So, well, listen, I feel we
could get more value out of this room
tonight, but this we don't have time. We
have to screen it again after this. Um,
okay. Well, that just adds to the
special nature of this evening. It is
it's quite remarkable to be able to
experience this exactly the way it was
in 1977
is you know it's this is really special
really special and then in terms of the
film itself I mean the universe of Star
Wars now has become so expanded and I do
want to say andor has been fantastic
[Applause]
um such a fan of andor and sort of
thinking about how the world has
expanded now I I also wondered within
And you know, as you bring filmmakers
into Lucasfilm to think about making
films that add to the Star Wars
universe, does this does the film, not
the print, but the film itself, does it
exist as the sort of the stone tablet?
Do do filmmakers go back to it? No, we
we I would say that this is the this is
the film that everyone starts with. When
we start talking about story, we start
talking about George's intent. Um, what
it is we're trying to build off of. Um
it's it is the gold standard. There's no
question. And um I mean we'll all we'll
definitely really experience I watch
about 5 minutes of this print when we
were researching for it. And it is
interesting how far back in time it
takes you and you really experience the
joy of the sets and the practical
effects where you can you know you can
enjoyably see the edges of some of them
as well. Um enjoyably experience the
edges. um
it it revolutionized film making at the
time. It revolutionized effects. I
wondered what excited you now about the
future of cinema and the sort of the
future of well I think what George
created with ILM and we did a really
wonderful documentary if you haven't
been able to see it in six-part series
on the beginning of men ILM. Uh, and
it's it really does capture what was so
unique about George's vision with where
cinema could go. And that's something
that we try to carry on in every single
thing we do. I mean, it's a constant
conversation. Innovation is something
that we know keeps pushing
cinema forward and it's all based on the
past, but we're constantly try trying to
reinvent the future. So, but still
feeling a love for some of the practical
effects constantly. It's because I I
think for many of us that kind of came
up through what what Stephen and George
and many of the pioneers of special
effects did. It it has everything to do
with recognizing
what's familiar in what you do. So to
just make it completely artificial, it
it loses its soul and you you have to
maintain what is real and then build off
of that. And Star Wars is 50. Star Wars
is 50. Unbelievable. It's just going to
be unbelievable. That is crazy. So we're
already talking about what that
celebration is going to be. Yeah, I'm
sure that's quite that's quite a plan.
What can you tell us now about the
future of Star Wars? What's coming up in
the next years? And if you want to tell
us anything extra special, that would
obviously be there, but it's up to you.
What what can we look forward to and
what what excites you about Star Wars at
50? What excites me now is, you know,
certainly with the success of Andor,
which has really been a 10-year journey,
beginning with Rogue One and then
building off of that in the series that
that Tony Gilroy created has really
expanded um genres that we can look at
and feel that we can sell stories in a
galaxy far far away with many, many
different genres. and John Favro working
with Mandalorian is very different from
what Tony was doing with with Andor and
that explores the genre of westerns. And
that's what George did. He he was
constantly looking at film and the way
stories build off of genre. And I I
really think that now we're in a
position where it broadens the
possibilities of stories and filmmakers
that we can bring in to tell stories
that mean something to them. It doesn't
necessarily have to connect to every
little thing that's been done in Star
Wars. It can actually be a standalone
story like an andor like a Rogue One
that then builds into many, many more
stories. So, we've got Mandalorian and
Grou next summer. Yes, next summer. And
then we have Sean Levy who's here
prepping right now with Starf Fighter.
So, that begins shooting in September,
which is one of the reasons I'm here.
Yeah. And um and we're very excited
about that with Ryan Gosling. And we're
just putting together the cast. It's
going to be pretty great. Yeah. Great.
Anything else you want to tell us? No,
I'm not going to tell you.
I'm going to tell you it is Star Wars.
Oh, Star. Okay. Breaking news. Um, okay.
Can I just say thank you again for
allowing us to do this this evening? Can
we please give the biggest round of
applause?
Thank you so much. Okay, enjoy the film
everybody.